<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mousemap on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/tags/mousemap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mousemap on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016, 2017 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 14:58:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hjdskes.github.io/tags/mousemap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 7: the resolutions stack page</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 14:58:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-7/</guid>
      <description>This week was a good week with loads of progress. I&amp;rsquo;ll just go through each item one by one, as usual.
MouseMap merged Last Friday I opened the pull request to merge the MouseMap widget. After a bit of a discussion around preferences, my mentor and I decided to merge ongoing work in a rewrite branch. This keeps the master branch functional (while still receiving improvements, such as adding new functionality to the ratbagd bindings or a Gtk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 6: progress!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 16:11:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-6/</guid>
      <description>This week Piper saw some progress again! Today I opened the pull request for the MouseMap that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the past two and a half weeks now. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the changes made since the last blog later; first, I want to highlight the other work I did the past week.
A major milestone this week is the merging of ratbagd and libratbag. While Piper shouldn&amp;rsquo;t notice any of this (it talks to ratbagd over DBus), it&amp;rsquo;s still a highlight I want to mention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 5: exams</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 16:52:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-5/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in my previous blog, the X.Org Foundation now wants us to blog every week. Whilst that means shorter blogs (last week&amp;rsquo;s was a tad long), it also means that there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to blog about if I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much in a week.
Such is the case for this week, sadly. It&amp;rsquo;s the last week of university, and so there are a few assignment deadlines that I needed to complete; I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to invest as much time into my project as I would have wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 4: the first sprint</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 20:47:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-4/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a long one, so grab a drink and a snack and buckle up! Incidentally, the X.Org foundation has asked us, the 2017 GSoC students, to blog weekly so from now on I will do so; which will also mean smaller blogs in the future.
I made a schedule to go with my proposal in which I divided the coding period into two week sprints to plan out my project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>