<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://hjdskes.nl/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016-2018 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 22:12:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hjdskes.nl/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: deploying Hugo-generated websites on personal GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 22:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I explained the workflow I use to update this website. It has never been particularly stable, and the process seemed far more complicated than it needed to be.
This week I attempted to update the theme of this website (sidenote: thanks Alexis Tacnet for your awesome theme and cooperation!). To pull in the theme&amp;rsquo;s files, I use git submodules. Apparently, this completely break git&amp;rsquo;s subtrees. I had enough of trying to maintain this complicated setup, so I started looking around for better ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hugo-generated websites on personal GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 22:07:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</guid>
      <description>The method described here is obsolete. The introduction still provides a nice overview of the problem, but please see my updated post for the actual steps and scripts!
 Hello, World!
As this is the first blog post on this website (and indeed, by myself), the introduction had to be done. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at this, though. If you want to know more about me, you can do that here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>