<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Piper on Jente Hidskes&#39; personal website</title>
    <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/tags/piper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Piper on Jente Hidskes&#39; personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016, 2017 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 17:53:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hjdskes.github.io/tags/piper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 3: mockups, mockups, mockups!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 17:53:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This will be a quick blog post on the previous two weeks. During this time, the community bonding period ended and the coding phase officially begun!
I spent most of the first week working on university projects, so that those are as done as they can be at this point and I have little else to work on besides Piper.
On the second week, I thought I would get a few days head start on my schedule by starting early on the mockups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 2: community bonding</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 16:01:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks have now passed since my introductory blog post, so as promised here is part two! The theme of this blog post is probably something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;preparation&amp;rdquo;, as that is what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing mostly.
The period between that of announcing the accepted student proposals and phase one is called the community bonding period. In this period students are supposed to get to know their mentors, their organizations, familiarize themselves with their projects (even more) and get everything ready to start off the coding period on May 30th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 1: an introduction!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:44:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after waiting for what felt like a very long time, I finally got the results of my Google Summer of Code (GSoC) application! I can happily say that one of my proposals has been accepted: I will work with Peter Hutterer to redesign and rewrite Piper. The synopsis of my proposal is as follows:
 Piper is an application frontend to libratbag and ratbagd, a library and system daemon to configure gaming mice respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>