<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fdo on Jente Hidskes&#39; personal website</title>
    <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/tags/fdo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fdo on Jente Hidskes&#39; personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016, 2017 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 17:35:55 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hjdskes.github.io/tags/fdo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 9: the button stack page</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 17:35:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-9/</guid>
      <description>When I discussed this project with my mentor before GSoC, he told me that the button mappings were going to be the most complicated piece. This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on precisely that and, well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say he wasn&amp;rsquo;t wrong &amp;#128521;
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along on GitHub, you&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking that it was a slow week. Indeed, there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been that much activity this week as in previous weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 8: the LED stack page</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 10:03:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-8/</guid>
      <description>Originally the plan for this week was to start working on the button mappings, however together with my mentor I decided that it&amp;rsquo;s better to do the LEDs first. This is because I was sure I could finish this in a few days, and button mappings is definitely going to take much longer than that. So, this week I&amp;rsquo;ll run you through the implementation of the LED stack page, and the coming weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on button mappings, profile support and a proper welcome screen, in that order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 7: the resolutions stack page</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 14:58:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-7/</guid>
      <description>This week was a good week with loads of progress. I&amp;rsquo;ll just go through each item one by one, as usual.
MouseMap merged Last Friday I opened the pull request to merge the MouseMap widget. After a bit of a discussion around preferences, my mentor and I decided to merge ongoing work in a rewrite branch. This keeps the master branch functional (while still receiving improvements, such as adding new functionality to the ratbagd bindings or a Gtk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 6: progress!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 16:11:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-6/</guid>
      <description>This week Piper saw some progress again! Today I opened the pull request for the MouseMap that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the past two and a half weeks now. I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the changes made since the last blog later; first, I want to highlight the other work I did the past week.
A major milestone this week is the merging of ratbagd and libratbag. While Piper shouldn&amp;rsquo;t notice any of this (it talks to ratbagd over DBus), it&amp;rsquo;s still a highlight I want to mention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 5: exams</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 16:52:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-5/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in my previous blog, the X.Org Foundation now wants us to blog every week. Whilst that means shorter blogs (last week&amp;rsquo;s was a tad long), it also means that there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to blog about if I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much in a week.
Such is the case for this week, sadly. It&amp;rsquo;s the last week of university, and so there are a few assignment deadlines that I needed to complete; I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to invest as much time into my project as I would have wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 4: the first sprint</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 20:47:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-4/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a long one, so grab a drink and a snack and buckle up! Incidentally, the X.Org foundation has asked us, the 2017 GSoC students, to blog weekly so from now on I will do so; which will also mean smaller blogs in the future.
I made a schedule to go with my proposal in which I divided the coding period into two week sprints to plan out my project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 3: mockups, mockups, mockups!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 17:53:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This will be a quick blog post on the previous two weeks. During this time, the community bonding period ended and the coding phase officially begun!
I spent most of the first week working on university projects, so that those are as done as they can be at this point and I have little else to work on besides Piper.
On the second week, I thought I would get a few days head start on my schedule by starting early on the mockups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 2: community bonding</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 16:01:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks have now passed since my introductory blog post, so as promised here is part two! The theme of this blog post is probably something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;preparation&amp;rdquo;, as that is what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing mostly.
The period between that of announcing the accepted student proposals and phase one is called the community bonding period. In this period students are supposed to get to know their mentors, their organizations, familiarize themselves with their projects (even more) and get everything ready to start off the coding period on May 30th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 1: an introduction!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:44:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after waiting for what felt like a very long time, I finally got the results of my Google Summer of Code (GSoC) application! I can happily say that one of my proposals has been accepted: I will work with Peter Hutterer to redesign and rewrite Piper. The synopsis of my proposal is as follows:
 Piper is an application frontend to libratbag and ratbagd, a library and system daemon to configure gaming mice respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>