<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Jente Hidskes&#39; personal website</title>
    <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Jente Hidskes&#39; personal website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016, 2017 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 20:47:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 4: the first sprint</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 20:47:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-4/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be a long one, so grab a drink and a snack and buckle up! Incidentally, the X.Org foundation has asked us, the 2017 GSoC students, to blog weekly so from now on I will do so; which will also mean smaller blogs in the future.
I made a schedule to go with my proposal in which I divided the coding period into two week sprints to plan out my project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 3: mockups, mockups, mockups!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 17:53:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This will be a quick blog post on the previous two weeks. During this time, the community bonding period ended and the coding phase officially begun!
I spent most of the first week working on university projects, so that those are as done as they can be at this point and I have little else to work on besides Piper.
On the second week, I thought I would get a few days head start on my schedule by starting early on the mockups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 2: community bonding</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 16:01:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks have now passed since my introductory blog post, so as promised here is part two! The theme of this blog post is probably something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;preparation&amp;rdquo;, as that is what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing mostly.
The period between that of announcing the accepted student proposals and phase one is called the community bonding period. In this period students are supposed to get to know their mentors, their organizations, familiarize themselves with their projects (even more) and get everything ready to start off the coding period on May 30th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC part 1: an introduction!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 15:44:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/gsoc-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, after waiting for what felt like a very long time, I finally got the results of my Google Summer of Code (GSoC) application! I can happily say that one of my proposals has been accepted: I will work with Peter Hutterer to redesign and rewrite Piper. The synopsis of my proposal is as follows:
 Piper is an application frontend to libratbag and ratbagd, a library and system daemon to configure gaming mice respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: deploying Hugo-generated websites on personal GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 22:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I explained the workflow I use to update this website. It has never been particularly stable, and the process seemed far more complicated than it needed to be.
This week I attempted to update the theme of this website (sidenote: thanks Alexis Tacnet for your awesome theme and cooperation!). To pull in the theme&amp;rsquo;s files, I use git submodules. Apparently, this completely break git&amp;rsquo;s subtrees. I had enough of trying to maintain this complicated setup, so I started looking around for better ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hugo-generated websites on personal GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 22:07:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.github.io/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</guid>
      <description>The method described here is obsolete. The introduction still provides a nice overview of the problem, but please see my updated post for the actual steps and scripts!
 &amp;ldquo;Hello, World!&amp;rdquo;
As this is the first blog post on this website (and indeed, by myself), the introduction had to be done. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at this, though. If you want to know more about me, you can do that here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>