<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://hjdskes.nl/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016-2019 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 17:31:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hjdskes.nl/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Cage: the Wayland kiosk</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 17:31:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/cage/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I made Cage publically available. Cage is a kiosk for Wayland. A kiosk is designed for running a single, maximized application and preventing the user from interacting with any other part of the system. You can read more about Cage on its project page.
I developed Cage as part of my home automation project. This is a hobby and learning project where I build my own, well, home automation system (from scratch, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cage: the Wayland kiosk</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.nl/projects/cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.nl/projects/cage/</guid>
      <description>Cage is a kiosk compositor for Wayland. A kiosk is a window manager (in the X11 world) or compositor (in the Wayland world) that is designed for a user experience wherein user interaction and activities outside the scope of the running application are prevented. That is, a kiosk compositor runs a maximized application at a time and prevents the user from interacting with anything but this application.
As such, user input such as moving, resizing, minimizing and unmaximizing windows is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gcolor3 has moved to GNOME&#39;s GitLab!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/gcolor3-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/gcolor3-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>Gcolor3 has moved from GitHub to GNOME&amp;rsquo;s GitLab instance! You can now find the repository at https://gitlab.gnome.org/World/gcolor3. This was suggested by GNOME developer Jeremy Bicha and finalized very quickly by Carlos Soriano, thanks both!
Being on GNOME&amp;rsquo;s GitLab is awesome, because Gcolor3 is now surrounded by other GNOME projects. This should make it easier to find for many people, but there are other benefits too. Since the move yesterday, I have already received nine merge requests!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gcolor3 version 2.3 is out!</title>
      <link>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/gcolor3-2.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hjdskes.nl/blog/gcolor3-2.3/</guid>
      <description>Finally, after a long period of sporadic commits, I released Gcolor3 version 2.3 out into the wild!
          This release was two years in the making (two years and twelve days, to be precise). It features 67 commits, resulting in a redesigned saved colors page, a redesigned headerbar and loads of under-the-hood changes. In this post, I want to go into a little more detail on the development and what led up to Gcolor 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>