<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github pages on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/github-pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github pages on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016-2019 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:54:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/github-pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An update on HTTPS certificate issues</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:54:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https-update/</guid>
      <description>For a little over a year now, this website has been enforcing HTTPS over both its www subdomain and the hjdskes.nl apex domain. These certificates are kindly provided automagically by GitHub in a partnership with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt.
In May, the certificate for my website expired. Expecting GitHub to be on top of this, at first I did not take any action. Some of you have reached out to me about the issue, which prompted me to contact GitHub to figure out why my certficate wasn&amp;rsquo;t being renewed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This website is now HTTPS only again!</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 11:41:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https/</guid>
      <description>From today, my website enforces HTTPS again! Github Pages have been supporting HTTPS since June 2016, so when my website was reachable only through hjdskes.github.io I got all of that for free. In fact, because HTTPS is the future&amp;trade;, I enabled Github Pages&amp;rsquo; enforce HTTPS feature in my website&amp;rsquo;s settings.
Since June 28 2019, I have removed the apex domain (`https://hjdskes.nl`) from my DNS records. [It turns out that GitHub does not support HTTPS for both the apex domain and the www subdomain](https://help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: deploying Hugo-generated websites on personal GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 22:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I explained the workflow I use to update this website. It has never been particularly stable, and the process seemed far more complicated than it needed to be.
This week I attempted to update the theme of this website. To pull in the theme&amp;rsquo;s files, I use git submodules. Apparently, this completely break git&amp;rsquo;s subtrees. I had enough of trying to maintain this complicated setup, so I started looking around for better ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hugo-generated websites on personal GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 22:07:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages/</guid>
      <description>The method described here is obsolete. The introduction still provides a nice overview of the problem, but please see my [updated post](/blog/update-deploying-hugo-on-personal-gh-pages) for the actual steps and scripts!  Hello, World!
As this is the first blog post on this website (and indeed, by myself), the introduction had to be done. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at this, though. If you want to know more about me, you can do that here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>