<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>https on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/https/</link>
    <description>Recent content in https on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016-2021 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:54:19 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/https/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An update on HTTPS certificate issues</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:54:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https-update/</guid>
      <description>For a little over a year now, this website has been enforcing HTTPS over both its www subdomain and the hjdskes.nl apex domain. These certificates are kindly provided automagically by GitHub in a partnership with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt.
In May, the certificate for my website expired. Expecting GitHub to be on top of this, at first I did not take any action. Some of you have reached out to me about the issue, which prompted me to contact GitHub to figure out why my certficate wasn&amp;rsquo;t being renewed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This website is now HTTPS only again!</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 11:41:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/https/</guid>
      <description>From today, my website enforces HTTPS again! Github Pages have been supporting HTTPS since June 2016, so when my website was reachable only through hjdskes.github.io I got all of that for free. In fact, because HTTPS is the future(tm), I enabled Github Pages&#39; enforce HTTPS feature in my website&amp;rsquo;s settings.
Since March, my website is also reachable through (www.)hjdskes.nl. When I set this up, I knew I would lose the ability to enforce HTTPS because up until yesterday, Github Pages did not support HTTPS for custom domains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
