<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>compositor on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/compositor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in compositor on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016-2019 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:12:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/compositor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cage 0.1.1 is out</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/cage-0.1.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 20:12:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/cage-0.1.1/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick notification to anyone following this website for Cage updates: I just released Cage 0.1.1. This release serves mostly for packagers that want to package Cage with wlroots 0.6.0, such as the Arch Linux packagers.
As such, not too much has changed between 0.1 and 0.1.1:
 Cage now drops root on startup on systems without (e)logind support (such as FreeBSD). The XKB_* environment variables can now be used to configure keyboard devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first pre-release of Cage</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/cage-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 20:24:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/cage-01/</guid>
      <description>Almost exactly four months ago I announced Cage, my Wayland compositor for a kiosk-like environment. To the uninitiated: a kiosk is designed for running a single, maximized application and preventing the user from interacting with any other part of the system. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen many in your life in malls, stores or even the dentist (how satisfied are you with your service?). Kiosks can also be used for much cooler things, though, such as running home automation systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Cage: the Wayland kiosk</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/cage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 17:31:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/cage/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I made Cage publically available. Cage is a kiosk for Wayland. A kiosk is designed for running a single, maximized application and preventing the user from interacting with any other part of the system. You can read more about Cage on its project page.
I developed Cage as part of my home automation project. This is a hobby and learning project where I build my own, well, home automation system (from scratch, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>