<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</title>
    <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws on Jente Hidskes&#39; website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016-2022 Jente Hidskes</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 17:12:18 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hjdskes.nl/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streaming a file from S3 to SFTP on AWS Lambda using Haskell</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/haskell-streaming-s3-to-sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 17:12:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/haskell-streaming-s3-to-sftp/</guid>
      <description>At work we embrace the serverless computing model and (typed) functional programming. My team&amp;rsquo;s Haskell service is therefore built upon, amongst others, AWS S3 and AWS Lambda. Earlier I wrote about how we deploy our Haskell binaries on AWS Lambda. Today I will write about something at a somewhat higher level. Let&amp;rsquo;s dig in!
The functional programming style encourages you to break down your problem into smaller problems. Smaller problems are easier to comprehend and reason about, and by decomposing your problem this way you often end up with a more general solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shiba project 🐕</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/shiba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 20:32:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/shiba/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a cool Saturday evening here in Stockholm. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting on the balcony with my new best friend by my side and a cool beer on the table. I just spun down a project that I hinted to over a year ago. Now&amp;rsquo;s a good time to reflect on it and explain what it was. Spoiler: it has to do with my new best friend here.
    In Sweden, buying a puppy is a well-controlled process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Nixified Haskell binary on AWS Lambda</title>
      <link>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/haskell-nix-aws-lambda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:28:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hjdskes.nl/blog/haskell-nix-aws-lambda/</guid>
      <description>For a current project (which I will be writing about soon!), I need to deploy a Haskell binary to AWS Lambda. Thankfully, there is a great library out there that allows Haskell code to interface with AWS Lambda. Unfortunately, Haskell is not officially supported so I needed to jump through some hoops in order to run my code.
In this post I describe the process I followed to make this work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
